{"tossups": [{"question": "This man created a system of \u201cburhs\u201d for the defense of his kingdom, which eventually became known as \u201cboroughs\u201d. This man\u2019s forces were attacked at Chippenham, which saw him retreat to Athelney. This man\u2019s life was chronicled by Bishop Asser, and he converted the Danish king Guthrum to Christianity. For ten points, name this Anglo-Saxon king of Wessex in the 800s AD, the only English king to be given the epithet \u201cthe Great\u201d.", "answer": "<b> Alfred</b> the Great (or<b> Alfred</b> I)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The Maori base their new year on the appearance of one star cluster in this constellation, to which the Parthenon is also oriented. In 1054, the first object cataloged by Messier appeared in this constellation, whose alpha star was named by Arabic astronomers for its following of the Pleiades. The Crab Nebula and Aldebaran are found in this constellation, which has been identified as Marduk, Nandi, and Io by various myth systems. For ten points, name this constellation, depicted by many ancient civilizations as a bull.", "answer": "<b> Taurus</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Astronomy"}, {}, {"question": "This leader ordered the genocidal Operation Anfal, carried out by Ali Hassan al-Majid; that operation included an attack on Halabja, where thousands of Kurdish people were killed by poison gas. This man was captured near Tikrit in a \u201cspider hole\u201d nine months after the U.S. invaded his country in 2003. For ten points, name this Ba\u2019ath Party leader, the former dictator of Iraq.", "answer": "Saddam<b> Hussein</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The destruction of Port Dover was used as an excuse to attack this city, but a hurricane allowed the defending side to move back from Brookeville. Robert Ross led the military force that attacked this city, following his success at the Battle of Bladensburg. Paul Jennings recounted Dolley Madison\u2019s efforts to save the portrait of George Washington from a burning building in this city. For ten points, name this city, burned by British troops near the end of the War of 1812.", "answer": "<b> Washington D.C.</b> (accept either) Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This artist\u2019s<em> The Battle of the Kearsarge and the Alabama</em> shows the Battle of Cherbourg during the American Civil War. This artist painted a nude woman looking toward the viewer while lounging next to a black cat and a black servant in<em> Olympia</em>. Raphael\u2019s<em> Judgement of Paris</em> inspired this man\u2019s painting of a nude woman who sits next to two fully clothed men at a picnic. For ten points, name this artist of <em>Luncheon on the Grass</em>.", "answer": "Edouard<b> Manet</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The \u201cimminent lawless action\u201d test was formed after Clarence Brandenburg, a member of this group, sued the state of Ohio. The first leader of this organization was a general whose forces committed the Fort Pillow Massacre. A revival of this group at Stone Mountain took place after it was depicted suppressing voters in D. W. Griffith\u2019s film<em> Birth of a Nation</em>. Nathan Bedford Forrest helped found, for ten points, what white supremacist organization?", "answer": "<b> K</b>u<b> K</b>lux<b> K</b>lan <b>Second Quarter</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This country won the Battle of Hanko during a war where this country was led by Risto Ryi. Earlier this country was forced to give up the Karelian Isthmus that was protected by its unfinished Mannerheim line. This country fought the Continuation war with Nazi allies, but later turned on the Nazis in the Lapland war. For ten points, name this Scandinavian country that was invaded by the Soviets in the Winter War.", "answer": "<b> Finland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Max Weber pointed to double-entry bookkeeping as marking the beginning of notions of this concept, whose ratio to income was examined in a 2013 work by Thomas Piketty. That work about this concept\u201cin the 21st century\u201d dismisses its \u201chuman\u201d type as a misnomer. Marx distinguished between its variable and constant forms in an uncompleted treatise he wrote about this concept. For ten points, name this economic concept that refers to the assets or wealth owned by a person, or to a good used in the production of other goods.", "answer": "<b> capital</b> (accept<b> Capital in the 21st Century</b> or<b> Das Kapital</b> before mention)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Economics"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "At a 2015 award ceremony, an actor impersonated this man threatening to kill Hannibal Buress. This man resigned from the board of Temple University, his alma mater, in 2014. In a 2005 deposition, this man admitted to illegally giving the sedative Quaalude to at least one woman. For ten points, name this actor and comedian who played Cliff Huxtable on a 1980s sitcom and has been accused by over 50 women of sexual assault.", "answer": "Bill<b> Cosby</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Robert J. Walker bribed Congressmen to approve of this action, which was negotiated by Eduard de Stoeckel. The Julian calendar was immediately replaced after this action, and Charles Sumner delivered a post-Civil War speech in favor of this action. Until the discovery of gold in the Klondike, this event was derided as \u201cSeward\u2019s Folly\u201d. For ten points, name this $7.2 million purchase, roughly equal to 2 cents an acre, in which the U.S. acquired the future 49th state.", "answer": "<b> Purchase</b> of<b> Alaska</b> (accept equivalents)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A U.N. Secretary General from this country died in a 1961 plane crash en route to peace talks over conflict in the Congo Crisis. Another leader from this country was a prime minister (+) assassinated in 1986 whose main suspect was Christer Pettersson. A king and military general from this nation died at the Battle of (*)</b> Lutzen and was known as the \u201cLion of the North\u201d. For ten points, name this Scandinavian country whose leaders included Dag Hammarskjold, Olof Palme, and Gustavus Adolphus.", "answer": "<b> Sweden</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Members of this religion prompted native Americans to attack members of the Baker-</b> <b>Fancher settlers in the (+)</b> <b>Mountain Meadows Massacre. This religion\u2019s founder wished</b> <b>to create a utopian \u201cZion\u201d after being forced by Lilburn Boggs\u2019s Extermination Order to migrate to (*) </b> Nauvoo, Illinois. For ten points, name this religion founded by Joseph Smith, whose members make up the majority of the population in Utah.", "answer": "<b> Mormon</b>ism or<b> Mormon</b>s (accept Church of Jesus Christ of<b> Latter Day Saint</b>s or<b> LDS</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After 100 days of exercise and incantations, members of this non-American movement believed they gained invulnerability to bullets. Members of this movement sieged the</b> <b>Legation Quarter until the (+)</b> <b>Eight Nation Alliance freed them.</b> <b>This movement was</b> <b>supported until 1901 by the Dowager Empress (*)</b> Cixi [see-shee] of the Qing [ching] Dynasty in hopes of ridding China of foreigners. For ten points, name this nationalist movement, also known as the Society of Righteous and Harmonious Fists.", "answer": "<b> Boxer</b>s (accept the Society of<b> Righteous and Harmonious Fists</b> until mentioned; accept <b>Boxer</b> Rebellion and equivalents) (7) <b>Bela Lyon Pratt created a statue of this man for his namesake fort in New Haven,</b> <b>Connecticut. Consider Tiffany wrote about the capture of this man in a tavern by Robert</b> <b>Rogers; this man was (+)</b> <b>observing the movements of British troops after the Battle of</b> <b>Long Island. He was purported to say, \u201cI only (*)</b> regret that I have but one life to lose for my country\u201d. For ten points, name this American spy who was executed during the Revolutionary War. ANSWER: Nathan<b> Hale</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}